outofstress.com 2019-04-16

# Privacy Policy – OutofStress.com

Last updated: 17th October 2018

Welcome to the Privacy Policy of *Outofstress.com. The privacy of our website visitors is very important to us, and we are committed to safeguarding it. This policy explains what personal information we connect, what we collect it for and how we safeguard this information.

Our website address is: [https://outofstress.com](https://outofstress.com/).

## What information we collect

Depending on how you interact with our site, we might collect some personal information from you. The following is the type of data we collect and why we collect it.

### Types of Data Collected

### 1\. Personal Data

**When you visit our site** – our web server will automatically collect your IP address, and unique online identifiers like your operating system, your browser software, browser version, device type, session start/stop time, time zone, cookie information, your general location (city and country), and general information regarding your online behavior like clicks, actions, search queries, installed apps, the pages of our Site that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other diagnostic data.

These details are pseudonimyzed (cannot directly identify you) and are collected for the purpose of delivering relevant content and ads and operating and improving our Service (including services from our partners).

**When you subscribe to our newsletter or contact us using a contact form on this site** – we will collect your name, IP address and email address. We use this information to send you relevant emails and marketing materials.

**When you comment on our site** – When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

### 2\. Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

Examples of Cookies we use:

**session cookies** (we use these cookies to operate our Service) and **preference cookies** (we use these cookies to remember your preferences and various settings).

**We use cookies for the following purposes:**

**(a) authentication** – We use cookies to identify you when you visit my website and as you navigate my website;

**(b) personalization** – We use cookies [to store information about your preferences and to personalize the website for you];

**(c) security** – We use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect my website and services generally;

**(d) advertising** – We use cookies to help me to display advertisements that will be relevant to you; and

**(e) analysis** – We use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services;

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>(Firefox);

(c) <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/> (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>(Internet Explorer);

(e) <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411> (Safari); and

(f) <https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy> (Edge).

Please note that blocking cookies may have a negative impact on the functions of many websites, including outofstress.com. Some features of the Site may cease to be available to you.

### 3\. Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 4\. Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

**Google Analytics –** We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of my website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies **.** Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

### 5\. Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### 6\. Third Party Cookies and Web Beacons

We use third party advertisements on outofstress.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

You can chose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

### 7\. Third Party Advertising

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by Google. Information about users’ visit to this site, such as number of times they have viewed an ad (but not username, date of birth, or any other personal information), is used to serve ads to users on this site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. For more information or to opt out of the DART cookie for Google, please [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

**Advertising Privacy Statement**

This site uses Google Adsense for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site. Google Adsense uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads. In addition we also publish standalone interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

### 8\. External Links

Our Website may display links to websites of third-party content providers, other than Our Partners. We do not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third parties, other than Our Partners, without obtaining your consent specifically permitting such disclosure. We do not endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices and content of such third parties. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to understand how they collect and process your Personally Identifiable Information.

### 9\. Affiliate Links

Outofstress.com participates in various affiliate programs like the amazon affiliate program. For more information, read our [affiliate disclosure](https://www.outofstress.com/affiliate-disclosure/). 

### 10\. Email Addresses

We may collect your email address, but only if you voluntarily provide it to us. This may occur, for example, if you sign up to receive an email newsletter, leave a comment or enter a promotion. We will use your email address for the purposes for which you provided it to us, and also from time to time to send you emails regarding the Site or other products or services that we believe may be of interest to you. You may opt out of such email communications at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” button in the email.

We will not share your email address with any third parties.

If you are a resident of a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), please refer to the section below entitled “Additional Rights of EEA Residents.”

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing. If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us, you can contact us at editor@outofstress.com If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners I work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

### Additional Rights of EEA (European Economic Area) Residents

If you are a resident of a country in the EEA, you have the rights, among others, to:

(i) access your personal data

(ii) ensure the accuracy of your personal data

(iii) the right to have us delete your personal data

(iv) the right to restrict further processing of your personal data, and

(v) the right to complain to a supervisory authority in your country of residence in the event that data is misused

If you believe that my processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by notice to me addressed to mail@shakejump.com.

## Who we share your data with

We use Third Party Advertising and other third party services like Website Analytics, Comment forms, Contact forms, Social Media Share Buttons on this site. These services will have access to your data such as your IP Address, Browser Version, Browser Type, Location etc. Please refer points 4 and 7 above.

Email address we collect in-case you sign up to our newsletter, contact us using the contact form on our site or by directly sending an email to our email address, or when you leave a comment are secure and not shared with anyone.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

## Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Questions, Suggestions and Complaints

If you have any privacy-related questions, suggestions, unresolved problems, or complaints you may contact us at editor@outofstress.com

If you reside or are located within the EEA, we may assist with all queries regarding our processing of Personally Identifiable Information. We request that you please attempt to resolve any issues related to your Personally Identifiable Information with us first. If you reside or are located within the EEA, you may also make a complaint to the supervisory authority for data protection in your country of residence (such as, for instance, the UK Information Commissioner’s Office for the UK) or seek a remedy through local courts if you believe that your rights have been breached.

### Changes to This Policy

We revise and evaluate this Policy periodically in light of changing business practices, technology and legal requirements. As a result, this Policy will be updated from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. Any change, update, or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on our Website.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Policy, our privacy practices, or to exercise your rights, please contact us by email at editor@outofstress.com
